<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: W3C | Everything is Gray]]></title>
  <link href="http://everythingisgray.herokuapp.com/category/w3c/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://everythingisgray.herokuapp.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-26T23:27:12-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://everythingisgray.herokuapp.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[James Barclay]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[XHTML is dead, (but don't worry)]]></title>
    <link href="http://everythingisgray.herokuapp.com/2009/07/02/xhtml-is-dead-but-dont-worry/"/>
    <updated>2009-07-02T16:06:10-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://everythingisgray.herokuapp.com/2009/07/02/xhtml-is-dead-but-dont-worry</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strike>Today</strike> On July 2, 2009, the W3C announced that the XHTML 2 working group will cease development by the end of 2009. Of course all this means is that more time, effort, and man power will be focused on the HTML 5 specification, which is going to drastically change the web, (just take a look at <a href="http://wave.google.com/">Google Wave</a>). This also means that we won&rsquo;t have any spec wars to deal with, which are almost as bad as format wars, (HD DVD vs. Blu-Ray anyone?)</p>

<p>From the W3C:</p>

<p><strong>XHTML 2 Working Group Expected to Stop Work End of 2009, W3C to Increase Resources on HTML 5</strong></p>

<p>2009-07-02: Today the Director announces that when the XHTML 2 Working Group charter expires as scheduled at the end of 2009, the charter will not be renewed. By doing so, and by increasing resources in the Working Group, W3C hopes to accelerate the progress of HTML 5 and clarify W3C&rsquo;s position regarding the future of HTML. A FAQ answers questions about the future of deliverables of the XHTML 2 Working Group, and the status of various discussions related to HTML. Learn more about the HTML Activity. <a href="http://www.w3.org/News/2009#item119">(Permalink)</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
